（チヨ）覚悟！
Prepare yourself!
（はたけカカシ）ぬぬっ？
（チヨ）はあーっ！
（うずまきナルト）うぐっ…
Why you--!
この！
ぬわっ！
（テマリ）はっ
（バキ）あっ
（エビゾウ）んっ
What do you mean by suddenly
pouncing on Kakashi Sensei like that?!
カカシ先生に いきなり
何すんだってばよ
You wrinkly old hag!
このシワくちゃババア
This old hag...is good...
（ナルト）このババア…
できる
あのときは よくも…
I'll never forget what
you did back then!
White Fang of the Leaf,
木こノ葉はの白い牙め
I shall avenge my son's death
by defeating you today!
息子の敵 今こそ
わしが成敗してくれる
（カカシ）ああ いや 私は…
Er...no, you see... I'm...
No questions or answers!
（チヨ）問答無用じゃ
Big Sister...
Take a good look at him!
（エビゾウ）姉ちゃんよ よく見ろよ
はっ？
（カカシ）アッハハ…
（エビゾウ）よく似とりはするが
He resembles him closely,
but this one is not the White Fang!
こいつは 白い牙ではねえよ
はあ？
Huh?
（カカシ）どうも
Uh...hello...
（エビゾウ）
それに 木ノ葉の白い牙は
Moreover, the White Fang
of the Leaf died long ago.
とうの昔に死んどる
（カカシ）アハハ
（エビゾウ）知らせを受けたとき
Remember?
‟息子の敵が討てなんだ”と
泣いて悔しがっておったろうが
When you got word of it,
you cried tears of regret,
since you could not avenge
your son.
（チヨ）うう…
Isn't that so, Sis?
（エビゾウ）のう 姉ちゃん
Gotcha, I was only pretending
to have gone senile.
（チヨ）な～んてな ボケたふり
アハッ アハッ… アハハハ…
（ナルト）なっ あ…
（カカシ）あ～
（テマリ･春野はるのサクラ）ああ…
（カンクロウ）
ぐああー！ ぐあっ…
うあっ ああ…
（バキ）カンクロウ
Kankuro!
Let me have a look.
（サクラ）診させてもらいます
（テマリ）頼む
Please do.
Kakashi Sensei and the rest of you,
please stand back a bit.
カカシ先生たちは
少し離れていてください
Got it.
分かったってばよ
ハア ハア…
ああっ！
（医療忍者）お… おい お前は…
H-Hey! You're...?
木ノ葉の医療忍者です
I'm a Leaf Medical Ninja.
♪～
～♪
The Medical Ninja's Student
They seem to have used
a heavy metal-based toxin.
（サクラ）重金属系の毒が
使われたようですね
It's the type that acts upon
the muscles to destroy the cells.
筋肉に作用して
細胞を破壊するタイプです
（チヨ）ほう
Just from that brief examination...
（医療忍者）あれだけの診察で…
You could tell that much...
（医療忍者）そこまで
His medical record please.
（サクラ）カルテを
Ah, here it is.
ああ これだ
This is the list
of toxic ingredients.
こっちが毒の成分表だ
There are blank spaces here
and there, but...
ところどころ 空欄もあるが
大体は予測できます
I can predict the general outcome.
心臓の筋肉が破壊されて
The cardiac muscle
will be destroyed,
and the heart could stop beating
at any time, so...
いつ停止しても
おかしくない状態ですから
It's difficult to say whether
we can concoct an antidote in time...
今から解毒薬を調合しても
間に合うかどうか
そんな… なんとかならないのか！
You don't mean that!
Isn't there anything we can do?
Please assemble the items
I request immediately.
すぐに 私が言うものを
そろえてください
Roger!
（医療忍者）はい
（サクラ）
かなりの荒療治になりますが
It's quite a crude treatment, but
it's the only option we have left.
１つだけ手があります
（我愛羅があら）ああ…
うっ ああ…
しっかりと押さえといてください
Hold him down firmly,
as this will be
a very delicate operation.
とてもデリケートな
作業になりますから
（バキ）ああ
（テマリ）分かった
- Right.
- Understood.
いきます んっ！
Here...goes...
（カンクロウ）ううっ
うわああ！ うっ…
Hold him down firmly!
（サクラ）しっかり押さえて
（一同）はい
- Yes!
I'll cause the Chakra
to flow into his body...
（サクラ）
チャクラを体に流し込んで
毒を細胞から浮き上がらせる
It will cause the toxin to
surface from the cells.
それを溶液に吸着させ
It will then be absorbed
by this liquid...
and extracted!
引き抜く
（医療忍者･バキ）あっ
あれが毒なのか
So that's the toxin...
（サクラ）よし
Yes!
次
Next!
（医療忍者たち）はい
- Yes!
Say... Kakashi Sensei...
なあ カカシ先生
Huh?
（カカシ）ああ？
What sort of person was
that White Fang of the Leaf
さっき
このばあちゃんが言ってた...
that this old lady here
was talking about?
木ノ葉の白い牙ってどんな人？
（チヨ）ん？
Well, that's hard to say...
（カカシ）どんなと言われても
Hmm, let's see...
そうだな
Well, in a word...
まっ ひと言で言うと…
He was my father.
俺の父親だ
なっ
Hey, you there...
お… お主
白い牙の息子か
Are you the son
of the White Fang?
Yes...
（カカシ）はあ…
どうりで… よく似とるわけじゃ
But of course...
So that's why you look
so much like him...
（カカシ）アッハハハ…
（カンクロウ）うっ うう…
ああ… あっ
うああ！ うっ…
- Next!
- Yes!
（サクラ）次
（医療忍者）はい
ハア
直接 毒抜きをしました
I directly extracted the toxin.
With this, his life should
no longer be in danger.
これで 命の心配は
いらないと思います
（一同）おおっ
（ナルト）さすが サクラちゃん
Way to go, Sakura!
ハァ ハァ
ハァ ハア…
ハア
But we still can't rest easy.
ですが まだ安心できません
I will now concoct an antidote
for the traces of toxin
これから僅かですが
体内に残留している毒に対する
解毒薬を調合します
that remain in his body.
Got it.
（バキ）分かった
必要なものがあれば
遠慮なく言ってくれ
If you need anything,
don't hesitate to ask.
Well then, first, I need a list
of the medicinal herbs
（サクラ）
では まずこの里で手に入る
薬草の一覧か何かを
that can be found in this village,
or something like that...
I'll bring it.
持ってきます
Please replace all of
his bandages.
包帯は 全て取り替えてください
Yes.
はい
それから点滴の用意を
And then prepare an IV drip.
Yes.
（医療忍者）はい
あと 抜き出した毒は
少量 抽出しておいてください
Also, please set aside a small amount
of the extracted toxin.
I will need it later.
あとで必要になりますので
（ナルト）サクラちゃん
Sakura... You're so cool.
格好いいってばよ
（さくら）ハァ
（チヨ）
まるでナメクジ娘のようじゃの
You're just like
the Slug Girl.
ちょうど お前のような
おなごが来るとは
To think that a girl just
like you would come here...
Yes, Lady Tsunade is my master.
はい
綱手つなで様は 私の師匠ですから
And besides, I was told by
my master to come here.
それに 私は師匠に言われて
ここへ来たんです
Here is the list of medicinal herbs.
（医療忍者）薬草のリストです
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
Say Sis... Time is flowing slowly,
but it's flowing.
姉ちゃんよ
時は ゆっくり流れているでよ
（砂すなの里さとの忍）
おい タカ丸まるが帰ってきたぞ
Hey! Takamaru has returned!
（砂の里の忍）バキ様
木ノ葉の里より返書です
Master Baki, a reply
has come from Leaf Village.
（バキ）ご苦労
Thank you for your troubles.
火影ほかげ様からだ
It's from the Hokage.
（ナルト）
綱手のばあちゃん なんだって？
What's Granny Tsunade saying?!
（カカシ）
ガイの班を増援部隊として
こちらに送ったそうだ
It says that Guy's squad has been
sent here as a reinforcement unit.
な…
ゲキマユ先生の班か
Bushy Brow Sensei's squad...?
ハハッ
I'll bet everyone has gotten stronger.
みんな 強くなってんだろうな
They even said that Neji
has become a Jonin.
ネジなんか もう上忍じょうにんだっていうし
よーし 俺たちってば
のんびりしてらんねえ
All right!
Now's no time for us to just
be hanging around!
すぐにでも 暁あかつきを追うってばよ
We should go after the Akatsuki...
right now!
（カカシ）追うのはいいけど
Going after him is
fine and well...
連中がどこに行ったか
分かってるの？
But do you know where
those guys have gone to?
（ナルト）ま…
うん…
（カカシ）あの
ちょっとお聞きしたいんですが
Um, excuse me for inquiring,
その後 暁の追跡は
どうなってるんです？
but what is the follow-up
to the Akatsuki pursuit?
（バキ）
まず 最初にカンクロウが
単独で出ていって ああなった
First, Kankuro set off by himself
and ended up like that.
その後 追跡部隊を出したが
まだ連絡はない
Next, a tracking unit was sent out,
but they've yet to contact us.
状況から考えて おそらく…
Judging from the situation,
it's likely that...
ほかに 里の上役が１名
行方不明になっている
One of the other village chiefs
has gone missing.
簡単にやられることはないと
思いたいのだが…
I don't like to think that
he could be taken out so easily, but...
（カカシ）では 完全に
見失ったということですか
Then, you mean to say
you've completely lost sight of him?
ああ そうだ
Yes, that is so.
（医療忍者）バキ様
（バキ）ん？
Lord Baki!
カンクロウが目を覚ましました
Kankuro has awoken!
（バキ･ナルト）あ…
（テマリ）カンクロウ 大丈夫か？
Kankuro, are you all right?!
（カンクロウ）なんだよ…
What, you're back already, Temari...?
もう帰ってきたのかよ テマリ
（テマリ）里の危機だと聞いてな
I heard the village was in crisis.
（カンクロウ）
心配かけて… すまねえな
Sorry...for making you worry.
（テマリ）バカ
You fool, don't talk
such nonsense!
くだらないこと言うな
（カカシ）カンクロウ君の
戦った場所まで案内してください
Please lead me to the place
where Kankuro did battle.
（バキ）あっ
（カカシ）
こう見えても 私 追跡のプロでして
I may not look it,
but I'm a pro at tracking...
少しでも ヤツらのにおいが
残っていれば…
If just the slightest trace
of their scent remains...
（カンクロウ）その必要はないぜ
There's no need of that.
うっ ああ…
俺の傀儡くぐつは…
My puppets...have all been recovered,
haven't they?
全部 回収してあるよな
I never imagined I'd find
this assortment
（サクラ）まさか砂隠すながくれにも
ここまで薬草がそろってるなんて
思ってもみなかった
of medicinal herbs here
in the Hidden Sand.
Still, the soil is not well suited
to growing medicinal herbs...
それでも 土地柄
なかなか薬草も育ちにくくて
In particular, we only have
a small amount of "Scurvy Grass."
特に友知草ともしりそうが僅かしか
No, this much is plenty.
（サクラ）
いいえ これだけあれば十分
I can make at least three antidotes.
解毒薬が３つは作れます
The enemy force was two
in number.
（カンクロウ）敵は２人
One of them led Gaara away...
１人は 我愛羅を連れてる
All you have to do it follow
Gaara's scent.
我愛羅のにおいを追えばいい
もし ２手に別れたとしても
Even if they split up into two,
one of them...
もう１人は… ぐっ
His smell is on that one...
そいつに においがついてる
In Crow's hand...
カラスの手に
服の１部を握らせておいた
I left him holding a scrap
of his clothes...
Even if you fall,
you won't fall without a fight...
（カカシ）
転んでもただでは起きない
Just what I'd expect from
a Sand Ninja.
さすがは 砂の忍しのび
うわっ ぐっ…
Kankuro! Are you all right?
カンクロウ 大丈夫か
Y-Yeah...
ん…
Ah, he came all the way
from Hidden Leaf Village for us.
（テマリ）ああ 木ノ葉から
わざわざ来てくれたんだ
Naruto...Uzumaki...is it?
（カンクロウ）うずまきナルトか
Hey...
押忍
（カンクロウ）そうか
I see...
Summoning Jutsu!
（カカシ）口寄くちよせの術
Eight Ninja Dogs,
at your service!
（パックン）八忍犬はちにんけん ただいま見参けんざん
パックン
Pakkun!
（パックン）おお ナルトか
Hey! Is that you, Naruto?!
Long time no see.
久しぶりじゃな
Pakkun, you haven't changed a bit,
have you?
パックン ちっとも変わってねえな
You haven't either.
お主もな
（ナルト）え… ええっ！
Eh?! I've grown quite a bit taller.
いや 身長だって
ほら ずいぶん伸びたってばよ
Yes, yes, but enough
of this chatter.
（カカシ）はいはい
おしゃべりは そのくらいにして
すぐに働いてもらうよ
I need you to get to work
right away!
I want you to determine
which way he headed.
そいつが どこに向かったか
突き止めるんだ
Now, go!
行け
We'll contact you right away
when we find something.
はい 分かったらすぐ連絡する
We're counting on you.
（ナルト）頼むってばよ
All right!
（ナルト）よーし！
パックンたちが戻ってきたら
出発だってばよ
When Pakkun and the others
get back,
we're heading out, I tell you!
すぐに準備を…
We've got to make preparations
right away...
（カカシ）ナルト ちょい待ち
Naruto, wait a minute!
ん？
（チヨ）カンクロウよ
Kankuro...!
（カンクロウ）あっ
Granny Chiyo?
Grandpa Ebizo, too?!
チヨバア様にエビゾウじい様
I want to hear it one more time,
directly from your mouth...
もう１度 お前の口から
直接 聞きたい
２人の敵のうち
１人がサソリであったことは
There is no mistake that one
of the two enemies was Sasori.
間違いないのじゃな
Is that correct?
うう…
どうなのよ カンクロウ
What about it, Kankuro?
ああ
Yeah... It was Sasori
of the Red Sand.
赤砂あかすなのサソリだと
みずから そう言った
He said so himself.
（カカシ）赤砂のサソリですか
Sasori of the Red Sand,
you say?
We might be able to find out more
about Akatsuki.
暁について
もう少し詳しく聞けそうですね
Please...
お願いします
できた
It's ready...
（医療忍者たち）おおっ
ちゃんと全部 飲んで
Be sure to drink it all down...
（カンクロウ）ううっ…
があっ
（サクラ）
これで もう大丈夫だと思います
You should be all right now, I think.
あとは しびれが引くまで
Just lie there and rest for
a while without moving
動かないで
ゆっくり寝ていてください
until the numbness goes away.
君たちも きょうは
ゆっくり休んでくれ
You should all get
a good night's rest as well.
I've prepared a room for you to use.
部屋は用意してある
（ナルト）
いや でも 早く我愛羅を…
But we've got to find Gaara quickly...
（カカシ）
お言葉に甘えさせてもらおう
I'll take advantage of
your kindness, if I may.
（ナルト）あ…
（カカシ）どうせ あしたから
強行軍になるんだ
We're going on
a harsh march from tomorrow.
んっ…
分かったってばよ
I understand...
（我愛羅）努力し
みずから切り開くしかないんだ
I just have to work hard and
carve out a future for myself.
１人きりの孤独な道に逃げず
And I must not run away
from my path of solitude.
そうすれば いつか…
If I do that, someday...
あいつのように…
Someday...I can be
（我愛羅）ぐずが 俺に指図するな
いい加減にしろ！
お前らを兄弟と思ったことはない
邪魔をすれば… 殺す
しかし あいつが あそこまでして言う
つながりとはなんなのか
今頃になって 俺にも
少し分かったことがある
苦しみや悲しみ 喜びも
ほかの誰かと
分かち合うことができるのだと
うずまきナルト
あいつと 戦い触れ合うことで
それを教わった気がする
あいつは 俺と同じ
苦しみを知っていた
そして 生きる道を変えることが
できることを教えてくれた
（カンクロウ）うずまきナルト
（ナルト）ん？
弟を頼む
フッ 任しとけってばよ
俺も いずれ火影になるからな
今から風影かぜかげに
貸しを作っといてやるよ
♪～
～♪
目指せ 生涯現役
きょうの お達者くらぶは
砂隠れのチヨバア様をご紹介します
ふん
ずばり ご趣味は？
釣り
シンプルな お答えです
では 得意なことは？
死んだふり
個性が光ります
では今 気になっていることは？
孫じゃ
おい 見てるか サソリ
ああー！
わしが たっぷり可愛がってやる
首を洗って待っておれよ
次回「隠居ババアの
決意」
木ノ葉の同盟国 砂の忍
きょうは 私たちが
特別授業を受け持つ
傀儡くぐつの術について
いろいろ教えてやろうじゃん
（テマリ）傀儡の術とは
指先から出した チャクラの糸で
傀儡を自在に操る術のことだ
（カンクロウ）これが
俺のかわいい傀儡たち
向かって左から 攻撃用の烏からす
防御用 山椒魚さんしょううお
そんで 捕獲用 黒蟻ありだ
烏と黒蟻の繰り広げる連携忍術
カラクリ演劇
黒秘技機々一発くろひぎききいっぱつは 見たが最後
あっという間に終劇しゅうげきじゃん
（テマリ）しかし
いつ見ても不気味な傀儡だな
（カンクロウ）
はっ この魅力が分からないとは
あわれじゃん
この毒針とか最高じゃねえか
なあ 烏
（テマリ）カンクロウ
傀儡ばかりに
うつつを抜かしていると
友達いなくなるよ
（カンクロウ）えっ あ…
これにて きょうの授業は終了
（カンクロウ）
あんな言い方しなくたって
いいじゃねえの
なあ 烏